Kobayashi (1994) observes that imagining the  
unessential can be a supremely challenging  
task because of the ways social constructions  
get naturalized and thus rendered opaque.  
Arguing that this opaqueness is sometimes so  
impenetrable that even the most critical  
perspectives can overlook it, she suggests a  
geographical method for moving beyond the  
occlusions of essentialism and naturalism.  
Scholars, she offers, might work to 'under- 
stand how discourses are produced and  
sustained, by uncovering and engaging social  
constructions on the very sites where they are  
produced and nourished' (Kobayashi 1994:  
78, emphasis mine). While Kobayashi does not  
elaborate much further, I take her suggestion  
to mean that the most challenging and difficult  
essentialisms to deconstruct are those so  
naturalized that they appear built into the  
very fabric of place. Or, as geographers  
Mitchell (1996) and Schein (1997, 2003)  
have argued, the seemingly unyielding materi- 
ality of cultural landscapes can so instantly  
and stealthily naturalize social categories that  
they appear pregiven.
Similarly, scholars of material culture  
studies cite Bourdieu's research on Kabyle  
society to elaborate on the ways arbitrary  
social values manifest in and get maintained  
by a 'world of things' (Tilley 2006b). That is,  
social orders, values, and ideologies are made  
to appear timeless and self-evident—natura- 
lized in part because of the relentlessly  
present materiality of the cultural objects  
that humans produce and use. In the words of  
Tilley, 'humans leave behind a vast array of  
artefacts which, quite literally, objectify their  
past presence .... Personal, social, and cultural  
identity is embodied in our persons and  
objectified in our things' (2006b: 60-61,  
emphases mine; also see Fowler 2010).
Moreover, people regularly embrace those  
objectifications. For example, museums, his- 
toric preservation districts, antique collec- 
tions, heirlooms, and so on all often play  
significant roles in imparting national, ethnic,  
or other social identities (e.g., Hagen 2008;  
Hoskins 2007; Mills 2010; also see Hoelscher  
and Alderman 2004; Till 2003). Similarly,  
historically significant material culture has  
often been preserved as stable repositories of  
tradition and roots in the face of disruptive  
forces of war, social change, capitalism, and  
modernity at large (Connerton 2009; Low- 
enthal 1996; Tilley 2006a; Wilson 1997). The  
same goes for indigenous material culture that  
acts as a source of tangible authenticity and a  
record of prior occupation in the landscape.13
Yet, while this work on the materialization  
of social values (and the embrace of those  
materializations) is suggestive for the Ala  
Kahakai, it does not fully describe what is at  
stake around the trail. The ways cultural  
landscapes and artifacts naturalize social  
categories and values through 'objectification'  
(Tilley 2006b) or 'materializing discourse'  
(Dwyer 2000, 2004; Schein 1997) do not quite  
explain the phenomena at work when it comes  
to the pervasiveness of essentialist interpret- 
ations for the project. I would like to suggest a  
move in the opposite direction. Rather than  
people producing concrete, naturalized  
expressions of culture and ideology through  
artifacts and landscape, I argue that the  
material landscape and its things exert their
nvirn occo1l-1a17-incr infinonro nn rEconnrcn
•..4167,.../ L41.
After all, absent the interpretive demands  
posed by the physical sites and artifacts along  
the trail, almost all native stakeholders  
actually- embody anti-essentialist conceptions  
of Hawaiian indigeneity in their daily life, if  
for no other reason that they almost all live  
more-or-less integrated within contemporary  
Hawaiian society."

